<?xml version="1.0"?>
<allhalf>
	<noofarticlestotal>15</noofarticlestotal>
	<noofarticlesinternet>4</noofarticlesinternet>
	<noofarticleshardware>3</noofarticleshardware>
	<noofarticlessoftware>3</noofarticlessoftware>
	<noofarticlesmiscellaneous>5</noofarticlesmiscellaneous>

	
	<poll>
			<pollquestion>The Best Low Budget Phone Company ?</pollquestion>
			<polloption1>Xiaomi</polloption1>
			<polloption1hits>56</polloption1hits>
			<polloption2>Lenovo</polloption2>
			<polloption2hits>1</polloption2hits>
			<polloption3>Micromax</polloption3>
			<polloption3hits>30</polloption3hits>
			<polloption4>Asus</polloption4>
			<polloption4hits>1</polloption4hits>		
	</poll>
	
	<article>
		<topic>Say Hello to Microsoft Edge</topic>
		<category>internet</category>
		<hits>2</hits>
		<likes>0</likes>
		<half>Microsoft comes all guns blazing with Microsoft edge to take on existing Browsers</half>
		<quarter>Microsoft Edge, would be lighter and faster than the existing Internet Explorer and will also come packed with lots of new features! Edge will be the default web browser in Windows 10 operating system.</quarter>
		<paramain>The project, codenamed &#x2018;Project Spartan&#x2019;, derived from Microsoft&#x2019;s veteran game Halo, is about to reach its completion as Microsoft has unveiled its new Web Browser which will eventually replace the dull Internet Explorer. Microsoft Edge, would be lighter and faster than the existing Internet Explorer and will also come packed with lots of new features! Edge will be the default web browser in Windows 10 operating system.</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Will it remain useful for office works as Internet Explorer was?</p><br/>As per the officials, Microsoft has claimed that the Microsoft Edge will inherit all the existing office tools from Internet Explorer, but will get a makeover in order to provide a better experience to the users. Along with that, all the security and safety programmes from the Explorer have been preserved, plus it will be loaded with new mechanisms to ensure privacy and safety to its users! With all these, Microsoft has made sure that their loyal users don’t find any difficulty in using the all new software.]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">What’s New?</p><br/>Along with all the existing features, Microsoft has made their software appealing with tons of new features. These new features include a built-in notation tool, a distraction-free reading mode, website information tool, and Cortana, a personal voice-assistant app for windows.<br/>The name Edge refers to the idea of being the edge of consuming and creating, said Mr Belfiore, Microsoft official. Along with the above features, simple things have also been taken care of, like note-taking and innovative interface of reading and consuming content. The Cortana built-in is loaded with all its Artificial intelligence programs, so it learns the things that one cares about and help one get things done.]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Edge, a Windows Developer’s Paradise!</p><br/>Microsoft, has taken care of the developers along with those of loyal veteran users and masses. Microsoft Edge will enable developers to engage with different sites and gives them a shot at starting to write some Web Code, which can later be put into an app via Web Extensions built into the software. The company is going to enable people to discover and engage with codes shared by developers on the Web.]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4>With all these additions to widely used Internet Explorer, Microsoft has taken a huge step in redefining the meaning of a Web Browser. Microsoft Edge will be available only for Windows 10 and further. Thank you Microsoft for taking care of everyone!</fullpara4>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article15.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article15a.png</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article15b.png</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article15c.png</image3>
			<image4>null</image4>
		</subimages>
		<date>24/04/2015</date>
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>
	</article>
	<article>
		<topic>Samsung Galaxy Note 3 Review</topic>
		<category>miscellaneous</category>
		<hits>32</hits>
		<likes>6</likes>
		<half>A fantastic successor of world&#x2019;s most successful Phablet.</half>
		<quarter>Whenever you think of Samsung, your focus will shift towards the Galaxy Series. And when you look for a Phablet, Note series won&#x2019;t disappoint you. The fact is that there hasn't been as successful a Phablet as the Galaxy Note series.</quarter>
		<paramain>Samsung essentially invented the Phablet, and it's been taking the idea from strength-to-strength ever since with every subsequent iteration. A stunning handset with plenty of power, a great screen, decent camera and days&#x2019; worth of battery life. One of the best multitasking smartphones around. Fantastic display, Lightning fast processor and performance, an excellent battery life and great multitasking. The Galaxy Note 3 was unveiled on September 4, 2013, with its worldwide release later in the month.</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Design:</p><br/>The company has selectively chosen slippery and glossy plastics which, to me, don’t exactly feel premium. The removable back panel is a bit of an oddity though. It is still most assuredly plastic but now it has a slightly soft faux leather effect texture and feel. The whole phone is only 8.3mm thick and altogether it’s very neat, clean and tidy to look at from the front.<br/><br/>The Skeuomorphic design elements, certainly do help on a practical level with the faux leather back texture and the surround’s ridged ‘pages’ providing excellent grip and making it easier to cope with the phone's proportions.]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Display:</p><br/>Talking about display, an expansive 5.7-inch touchscreen embedded in the front of the Galaxy Note 3, looks fantastic. It’s nothing short of spectacular with incredibly robust colour, contrast and brightness. Sharpness for a display of this size is impressive as the screen has full HD 1920x1080 pixel resolution and a pixel density of 386 ppi.<br/><br/>Note 3 boasts of its awesome brightness for more satisfying use. Generally, the Galaxy Note 3 is particularly capable of usage in bright conditions, even in direct sunlight. It’s great for watching full feature length films on the go, viewing angles are also great, meaning you can share whatever you’re watching.]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Hardware:</p><br/>The Samsung Galaxy Note 3 comes with tons of storage. Coming with an internal storage capacity of 32GB, the smartphone provides microSD HC card supports up to 64 GB, which is sufficient enough! The phone comes with Qualcomm Snapdragon 800 with mighty 3GB of RAM and an Adreno 330 graphics processing unit. The processor is clocked at lightning fast 2.3GHz. So, performance is just ridiculous, in a good way.]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Camera:</p><br/>The camera is a 13-megapixel with a single LED flash plus both 1080p and 4k video capture, and supports many features of the Samsung Galaxy S4, including the Samsung Galaxy Camera style UI and a few of its modes. There’s a selection of the usual controls in the top left for flash, digital stabilisation and sound recording for video while a Settings menu opens up for things like picture size, burst mode toggle and tap-to-capture.<br/><br/>It might not be anywhere near the level of the Samsung Galaxy S4 Zoom, Samsung Galaxy Camera or Nokia Lumia 1020, but, just like the Samsung Galaxy S4, it’s highly usable as a quick and easy point n shoot option with fantastic results which most users will likely enjoy.]]></fullpara4>
			<fullpara5><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Battery:</p><br/>With a hunky capacity of 3200mAh, Note 3’s battery backup is simply spectacular. From 100 per cent charge, Note 3 provides an all-round usage of the smartphone for over 36 hours. The charger is quite powerful and can charge the battery from 0 to 100% in mere 4-5 hours. And without using some of the characteristic features of the Galaxy series, the phone would last for around 4 or 5 days!]]></fullpara5>
			<fullpara6><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Conclusion:</p><br/>The best thing about Galaxy Note 3 is that it's a Samsung handset where the company does continue to truly innovate and make genuine improvements to the user experience. The S-Pen has been refined extensively, however, and Samsung certainly intends to continue showing sometimes skeptical consumers why a stylus is a good thing to have.<br/>So, if you are a data user and want a large smartphone, not many phones in the market would beat the Samsung Galaxy Note 3.]]></fullpara6>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article14.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article14a.png</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article14b.png</image2>
			<image3>null</image3>
			<image4>Pictures/article14c.png</image4>
			<image5>Pictures/article14d.png</image5>
			<image6>null</image6>
		</subimages>
		<date>30/04/2015</date>
		<author>Aman Sharma</author>
	</article>
	<article>
		<topic>High-End vs. Mid-Range Smartphones</topic>
		<category>miscellaneous</category>
		<hits>18</hits>
		<likes>2</likes>
		<half>Do High End phones really offer something extraordinary and are they really value for the money?</half>
		<quarter>It is quiet captivating that how in the past few years smartphones changed the communication industry around us. There has been an exponential growth in terms of size, design, speed, software and camera since the first smartphone came out.</quarter>
		<paramain><![CDATA[So, this is a usual quarrel between the youngsters these days that whose smartphone is better.<br/>Some have better camera, some better processor and some are just stylish enough to argue for. This vast list of specifications never ends.]]></paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[It is quiet captivating that how in the past few years smartphones changed the communication industry around us. There has been an exponential growth in terms of size, design, speed, software and camera since the first smartphone came out. For the record, most of the smartphone manufacturers are announcing their new flagship phones roughly every three months.<br/><br/>I remember when Samsung launched the Galaxy Note back in 2011, no one would have thought that the 5 inch form factor would be more than a regular stuff today.]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">But, are these changes really worth?</p><br/>I mean,on one side there’s a huge range of smartphones under 20k which can offer almost all the normal specifications and can run whatever thrown at them and on the other hand there is whole other range of high end fascinating smartphones with a price tag of above 50k. The point being made here is that are these phones really worth so much? <br/><br/>I agree that these high end phones have a much better built factor, have a premium and classy touch, but as far as the performance is concerned, there no such significant difference between the two sets of phone. Clearly there is some exclusivity in all the brands such as HTC’s Gesture controls, Sony’s camera controls, Samsung Galaxy Note’s Pen controls, etc. But these controls do not come handy all the time. <br/>The conclusion is that these are not so charming features to make these phones a must buy.]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3>On the other hand there&#x2019;s the Chinese giant Xiaomi which has been producing world class mid- range budget phones. Also some of these products are so designed that these just work perfect with the components they are made with, resulting in a smooth experience.</fullpara3>
			<fullpara4>Also, people at least in India have this mentality to have the best with them. This results in people buying the high end phones. Hence, they do not buy according to their needs but just for showing it off. For instance, if a smartphone is specifically designed for the business class, how can possibly a 16 year old be benefited by that phone!</fullpara4>
			<fullpara5><![CDATA[It is evident that high priced are better in every aspect in comparison to the mid-ranged phones, but we all can be clever enough to carefully analyze and invest according to our needs. <br/>Also, Micromax is the highest selling smartphone in India because it concentrated on reaching the mass with its mid ranged phones.]]></fullpara5>
			<fullpara6>Technology is all about changes and innovations which invests in our better future. Mobile phones have now become an integral part of our lives. Hence this is one of the most rapid growing industries in the world.</fullpara6>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article13.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article13a.png</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article13b.png</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article13c.png</image3>
			<image4>null</image4>
			<image5>Pictures/article13d.png</image5>
			<image6>null</image6>
		</subimages>
		<date>28/04/2015</date>
		<author>Rishabh Yadav</author>
	</article>
	<article>
		<topic>GDDR3 vs. GDDR5</topic>
		<category>hardware</category>
		<hits>104</hits>
		<likes>8</likes>
		<half>The battle between two generations of Graphic Cards!</half>
		<quarter>One of the biggest decision for a gamer would be to buy a performance packed DDR5 with more memory bandwidth or DDR3 with more total memory but less bandwidth. Those who already made the decision, best of luck. But those who still haven't decided, we will make sure that you will not regret your decision later.</quarter>
		<paramain><![CDATA[One of the biggest decision for a gamer would be to buy a performance packed Graphic DDR5 with more memory bandwidth or Graphic DDR3 with more total memory but less bandwidth. Those who already made the decision, best of luck. <br/><br/>But those who still haven't decided, we will make sure that you will not regret your decision later. Most of the people ask to whether buy a 4GB DDR3 or a 2GB DDR5. They both have a bit of difference which may lead to significant performance gap depending on the graphics settings enabled. These debates have escalated quite quickly since the launch of Xbox one and PS4.]]></paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1>First thing, both have to do with the memory bandwidths. And the shorter answer to your question is that GDDR5 results in faster memory bandwidth than the GDDR3. So, if you just consider the memory bandwidth, then GDDR5 easily wins. But now we will go a little deep into the details!</fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[DDR5 is the more recent type of double data RAM, and it is just for the graphic card. Being more recent and loaded with latest technologies, it works roughly twice as fast as the DDR3 Card. This plays an important role in allotment of memory bandwidth for your video memory. The formula for memory bandwidth is given by the following: Memory * Bus width * DDR multiplier. <br /><br/>This is how fast a graphics card can access and exchange information with its pool of video memory. This memory clock can be seen on most graphics cards technical info and can be compared to a vehicle's speed limit on the highway. The bus width can also be seen on graphics card technical info. It can be either 128 bits or 256 bits. This is the number of information channels through which data can go through between a GPU and VRAM. So, it can be compared with the number of lanes on the highway. <br/><br/>Lastly, there's the DDR3 or DDR5, which can be compared to the interval between when the next car in a lane can travel.]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3>For example, DDR3 allows 1 car into each lane every 10 seconds, while DDR5 allows 1 car into each lane every 4 seconds. Clearly, DDR5 would allow more cars in the end, but that doesn't mean that the total bus width and memory of the DDR3 or DDR5 won't play any role in it.</fullpara3>
			<fullpara4>Memory bandwidth is important to ensure that the graphics card is able to make efficient use of the VRAM. For example, if everything in the two graphics cards is the same except for its capacity and type. Consider the first one to be 1 GB DDR5 and other one to be 2 GB DDR3. It is clear that 1 GB of DDR5 would be able to make a better use of its pool memory. But it can get complex if one is 1 GB DDR4 with 200 MHz clock and 128 bit bus and the other one to be 2 GB DDR3 with 500 MHz clock and 256 bit bus. Here, clearly the DDR3 will emerge as the winner.</fullpara4>
			<fullpara5>But if the clock speed is the same and also the bit bus is the same, then go for the DDR5 card as it would provide as much bandwidth as required at high resolution.</fullpara5>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article1.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article1a.png</image1>
			<image2>null</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article1b.png</image3>
			<image4>null</image4>
			<image5>null</image5>
		</subimages>
		<date>23/04/2015</date>
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>
	</article>		
	<article>
		<topic>Two Must Have Navigation Apps</topic>
		<category>software</category>
		<hits>37</hits>
		<likes>5</likes>
		<half>Love to travel? These apps might just help you.</half>
		<quarter>If you are a person who loves to travel to unknown places and explore them, then you must be having a navigation app installed on your device and you might have been using it a lot. But us the app you use is really the best? Let us help.</quarter>
		<paramain>If you are a person who loves to travel to unknown places and explore them, then you must be having a navigation app installed on your device and you might have been using it a lot. But us the app you use is really the best? Or are there any other apps that have many more features and would come handy? Here at Technocratism, we have tested various apps, and selected two apps that would work perfectly if you have a smartphone and it&#x2019;s charged! Have a look.</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">1)	Google Maps :  </p><br />   An owner of android device would know how powerful this app is! This app, comes preinstalled and loaded with all the features for free! Honestly, Google maps is a better app than any other navigation software that come preinstalled on iPhones. With over 220 countries and territories, Google provides the widest area of navigation with this app. On top of that, it comes with voice enabled GPS navigation and live traffic analytics, which would allow you to select the best route and reach to your destination on time. But just one con, you need to be connected to an internet connection for that.]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[Play Store Link:<br />   <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.maps&hl=en">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.maps&hl=en</a>]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">2)	Here Maps :    </p><br />  You all might be thinking why we are discussing another app when Google provides all the need features. But where Google maps stop working, there we have Here Maps. Yes. The only con of Google maps is that it requires data connection. Although you can save a map for future use, but it is still in beta stage and users might find it difficult to use it. So, with here maps, you can have voice enabled GPS navigation along with over 200 countries and territories with 3D rendering of buildings. And all these offline! Just download the required map from the app for free and use it. Downloads are also classified in an elegant manner, ranging from states/counties to countries to continents to the entire world! ]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4><![CDATA[Play Store Link:<br />   <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.here.app.maps&hl=en">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.here.app.maps&hl=en</a>]]></fullpara4>
			<fullpara5><![CDATA[So now, never worry about getting lost in a new place. These two apps will always be at your rescue!]]></fullpara5>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article2.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article2a.png</image1>
			<image2>null</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article2b.png</image3>
			<image4>null</image4>
			<image5>null</image5>
		</subimages>
		<date>22/04/2015</date>
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>	
	</article>		
	<article>
		<topic>Google Fiber and India: Possible</topic>
		<category>internet</category>
		<hits>21</hits>
		<likes>5</likes>
		<half>The ultra-fast internet connection by google is already available in 3 cities. But when is it coming to India?</half>
		<quarter>Google fiber is a high speed internet service provided by Google Limited. And by High Speed, Google really means high speed. It provides speed 100 times faster than a regular internet connection. Yes, 100 times faster and when you will hear the speed, you might also want a google fiber connection in your house. </quarter>
		<paramain>The ultra-fast internet connection by google is already available in 3 cities in US and 25 more cities will be added soon. But when is it coming to India?</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[Most of the people already know what Google Fiber is and why so many people are waiting for it. But for those who don&#x2019;t know, Google fiber is a high speed internet service provided by Google Limited. <br/><br/>And by High Speed, Google really means high speed. It provides speed 100 times faster than a regular internet connection. Yes, 100 times faster and when you will hear the speed, you might also want a google fiber connection in your house. The speed it provides is at 1000Mbps or 1Gbps! Just imagine watching real-time Television, on an internet connection, without buffer and that too in HD!]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[This is the power google fiber brings to your hands. And when you are not watching a TV, imagine downloading a full HD movie in just 33 seconds. That&#x2019;s the internet speed Google provides in three cities of the United States of America in household connections.<br/><br/> And that&#x2019;s not all. Google fiber also provides you a network box with a capacity of 2 Terabytes. Yes, and in this, you can store your recorded videos for television and watch them whenever you want. At such limitless Internet connection and Television recording, anyone would want to have a Google Fiber connection at their homes. But when is it actually coming to India?]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[Talks are on between the IT ministry of the central government and the Google Fiber team to bring this amazing optical fiber based broadband services in India. An official from the IT ministry said, &#x201C;We are keen to partner a company like Google in furthering Digital India plan. Modalities have to be worked out first.<br/><br/> Although Google officials haven&#x2019;t yet shared about their plans related with Google Fiber in India, but they admitted that they are working closely with the Indian Government on several projects. ]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4><![CDATA[On the other hand, an official from IT Ministry said to The Hindu, that a team from Google are arriving in India shortly to make feasibility studies about Google Fiber in India. There are many obstacles that have to be cleared before making Google fiber available in India. <br/><br/>But if government grants all the required licenses to Google Limited, then India will witness a major boost to its Digital India project and Broadband Internet connections.]]></fullpara4>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article3.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>null</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article3a.png</image2>
			<image3>null</image3>
			<image4>null</image4>
		</subimages>
		<date>20/04/2015</date>
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>	
	</article>		
	<article>
		<topic>Android Wear Update To Take On Apple Watch</topic>
		<category>hardware</category>
		<hits>30</hits>
		<likes>6</likes>
		<half>Wi-Fi, gestures and emoji&#x2019;s come to your wrist.</half>
		<quarter>The way Apple Watch&#x2019;s release stormed the markets and tech enthusiasts, Google was bound to make their fans and customer happy. The wait of all their fans has finally come to end. Google has finally launched its most awaited update for android wear which brings it level to level with apple watch in almost all aspects and also betters out at some places!</quarter>
		<paramain>Wi-Fi, gestures and emoji&#x2019;s come to your wrist.</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[The way Apple Watch&#x2019;s release stormed the markets and tech enthusiasts, Google was bound to make their fans and customer happy. After several weeks of hard work, the wait of all their fans is finally coming to end. Google has finally launched its most awaited update for android wear which brings it level to level with apple watch in almost all aspects and also betters out at some places!<br /><br />This update has finally brought the Wi-Fi supports, hand drawn emoji&#x2019;s and gesture support to the wrist. With its hand drawn emoji&#x2019;s, you need not reply anyone with boring text or speaking to your phone, rather draw an emoji yourself on the watch and send it away, cutting out awkward talk with your wrist.]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[Another important thing this update has brought is the Wi-Fi. With Wi-Fi built in many of the android wear devices, this is a huge and a very important update. Now you can roam in your Wi-Fi enabled house and keep receiving important notifications even if you are out of range of your phone&#x2019;s Bluetooth network!<br /><br /> And not only this, Google has also added the Google cloud support on the android wear devices, so now backup your data using your watch itself.<br /><br /> Plus, a new feature in tests, connects your watch to available Wi-Fi hotspots in the area!]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[Keeping in mind the more battery consumption due to Wi-Fi connectivity, Google has developed a low screen mode software to run on your devices, which would save your battery! Along with this, developers can tweak with the information and decide whether it would go to the &#x2018;low power screen&#x2019; or not!<br /><br /> The other change your screen will see along with low power mode will be gestures. Just flick you hand over the top of watch and see the next notification, without even touching the screen! But with this, there&#x2019;s a risk of calling someone by mistake, because of some random gestures of day to day life, but Google has taken care of this. Google said that it&#x2019;s not a destructive weapon, but just a way to scroll up or down!]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4>With all these updates, Google has aimed at the apple watch and has also brought happiness to their customers. They also said that a second huge update is on its way and that update would make watch even more useful. We are hopeful!</fullpara4>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article4.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article4a.png</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article4b.png</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article4c.png</image3>
			<image4>Pictures/article4d.png</image4>
		</subimages>
		<date>15/04/2015</date>
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>
	</article>	
	<article>
		<topic>Difference Between IPv4 And IPv6</topic>
		<category>internet</category>
		<hits>38</hits>
		<likes>2</likes>
		<half>It&#x2019;s been quite a time since all the computer engineers have started advising to upgrade from IPv4 to IPv6. </half>
		<quarter>IPv4 (Internet Protocol Version 4) is the fourth revision and the most used version of the IP (Internet protocol). It is designed for use in systems of packet switched computer communications networks. IPv6 (Internet Protocol version 6), is the newest version of the IP, as mentioned above.  </quarter>
		<paramain>It&#x2019;s been a quite a time since all the technicians and computer engineers have started advising you to upgrade from your 32 bit scheme of IPv4 to 128 bit scheme of IPv6. But what actually is the difference between them and what is the necessity to upgrade?The first thing required to understand the difference between IPv4 and IPv6 is to know what IP address stands for.</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">What is an IP address?</p><br/>IP address, standing for Internet Protocol Address, is a unique string of numbers separated by full stops that identify each computer using the internet protocol to communicate over a network. It also specifies the technical format of the packets to connect to a network. IP by itself can be compared to the postal system.<br/><br/> It allows the system to pick a package and drop it to desired address without sharing any direct link between you and the recipient. IP address is most of the times combined with Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) to form TCP/IP so that they can send messages back and forth for a period of time. There are currently two versions of this IP address system: IPv4 and IPv6.]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">IPv4:</p><br/>IPv4 (Internet Protocol Version 4) is the fourth revision and the most used version of the IP (Internet protocol). It is designed for use in systems of packet switched computer communications networks. IPv4 uses a 32-bit address scheme which allows 2^32 addresses, which comes to just over four billion addresses. Seeing the steady growth of the internet, it is already expected that the total number of users will surpass the number of addresses allowed by IPv4. To fulfil this ever increasing demand, a new internet messaging scheme has been in development since mid-90s, called the IPv6.]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">IPv6:</p><br/>IPv6 (Internet Protocol version 6), is the newest version of the IP, as mentioned above. It is also called as the IPng, which stands for Internet Protocol next generation. Compared to the 32 bit address scheme, IPv6 uses 128 address scheme to store the Internet addresses. It has been designed to allow the internet to grow in terms of number of users and also the total amount of data transferred. It is expected that IPv6 will coexist with IPv4 for few more years before taking over the entire internet network.]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Difference between IPv4 and IPv6:</p><br/>The major difference between IPv4 and IPv6 is that, the IPv4 uses a 32 bit address scheme while IPv6 uses 128 bit scheme. Also, IPv4 is written in binary and then converted to decimal as four numbers separated by periods. For example, 1.172.255.240 is an IP address. Whereas IPv6 is written in hexadecimal and separated by colons. An example for IPv6 address is written like 5hhe:1700:2121:7:101:f8ff:fe21:67cf. On top of this, IPv6 has improvised on the following aspects of the IP:<br/><br/>1.	Reducing Private address collisions<br/>2.	Auto-configuration<br/>3.	Better Multicast routing<br/> 4.	Built in privacy support<br/>5.	Easy administration<br/>6.	Flexible extensions<br/>7.	True quality of service(QoS)]]></fullpara4>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article5.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article5a.png</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article5b.png</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article5c.png</image3>
			<image4>null</image4>
		</subimages>
		<date>15/04/2015</date> 
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>
	</article>
	<article>
		<topic>Why does Google Load So Fast</topic>
		<category>internet</category>
		<hits>17</hits>
		<likes>3</likes>
		<half>Most of us use Google.com to check if we are connected to internet, because it loads fastest among all the other websites.</half>
		<quarter>If you use internet, then you must have used Google at least once in your life. Once would be highly limiting the stats, because almost 70% of searches made on the Internet are made using the Google.com search service. And if you have used it, you might have noticed that no matter how fast or slow the internet connection is but, the pages of Google open faster than any other website.</quarter>
		<paramain>Most of us use Google.com to check if we are connected to internet or not, because it opens the fastest among all the other websites. But why does that happen? We will see.</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[The Internet was made public for the world before more than 25 years. Since then, the technology has evolved at an exponential rate. Somewhere around the end of 90s, a super power of the Internet world was being designed in a small garage of the United States. Since then, the small company didn't look back and grew bigger and bigger, fulfilling all the expectations of the public.<br/><br/> With such high popularity and control over the internet, Google took another huge step by combining the servers of the United States with itself and built the best servers in the world. These servers now govern the internet all over the world. All the data sent and received is regulated by these servers located in the no-fly zone area of California.]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[If you use internet, then you must have used Google at least once in your life. Once would be highly limiting the stats, because almost 70% of searches made on the Internet are made using the Google.com search service. And if you have used it, you might have noticed that no matter how fast or slow the internet connection is but, the pages of Google open faster than any other website.<br/><br/> Many people wonder why this thing happens. Read on to find out why Google loads faster than any other website.]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[The internet service is not continuous as many wonder. It is discrete in form and the data is transferred in the form of small packets. To open, browse or stream anything on the internet, your computer needs to receive these packets, process the data in them and then convert it to usable form as we see it. <br/><br/>Even though the data sent is discrete, the packets sent are discrete in nature as well. At first, one packet of data is sent. Then if more data is needed, 2 packets are sent. If even more data is needed, it send 4 packets of data. This goes on until the entire webpage is received in the form of data packets. This rule of sending and receiving 1,2,4,8... Packets holds true for all the websites but Google.]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4><![CDATA[To load a Google webpage, the server doesn't send 1,2,4,8... Packets but, it calculates the total number of data packets needed and sends them all together. For example, if a normal webpage needs 15 packets of data to load, the server will send 1 packet then 2 packets then 4 packets then 8 packets to load the page. But if Google webpage needs 15 packets of data to load, the server sends all the 15 packets of data together and the page loads quickly!<br/><br/> Amazing, isn't it?]]></fullpara4>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article6.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article6a.png</image1>
			<image2>null</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article6b.png</image3>
			<image4>null</image4>
		</subimages>
		<date>14/04/2015</date>
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>
	</article>
	<article>
		<topic>Mortal Kombat X Review</topic>
		<category>software</category>
		<hits>9</hits>
		<likes>1</likes>
		<half>So the new Mortal Kombat is here! Mortal Kombat X is the 10th installment in Mortal Kombat series.</half>
		<quarter>Developed  by NetherRealm Studios, High Voltage Software it was released on April 14 for Play Station 4, Xbox One and Windows. According to sources, ps3 and Xbox 360 versions will be available on Q2 or Q3 of 2015. An iOS version was released on April 7, Android TBA.</quarter>
		<paramain>So the new Mortal Kombat is here! Mortal Kombat X,Developed  by NetherRealm Studios, High Voltage Software  is the 10th installment in Mortal Kombat series. It was released on April 14 for Play Station 4, Xbox One and Windows. According to sources, ps3 and Xbox 360 versions will be available on Q2 or Q3 of 2015. An iOS version was released on April 7, Android TBA.</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1>Like previous entries in the series, Mortal Kombat X is a fighting game in which two players fight against each other using a variety of attacks, special moves, and gruesome Fatalities. The energy meter, first introduced in the previous Mortal Kombat game, allows players to perform techniques such as "X-Ray" special moves.</fullpara1>
			<fullpara2>MKX features two new types of finishing moves: Quitality, which will instantly kill a player's character if they quit during a multiplayer match and Faction Kills, finishing moves tied to each of the game's five factions. Brutality finishing moves make a comeback from Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3 in the form of enhanced versions of certain moves that are triggered when they are used to give the opponent the last attack in a round.</fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[With 10th installment they have also introduced 8 new characters! How awesome it would be!<br/><br/><br/>Characters include:<br/><br/>Cassie Cage<br/>Takeda<br/>D'Vorah<br/>Tremor<br/>Erron Black<br/>Ferra Torr <br/>Jacqui Briggs<br/>Jason Voorhees<br/>Kotal Kahn<br/>Kung Jin<br/>Predator ]]></fullpara3>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article7.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article7a.png</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article7b.png</image2>
			<image3>null</image3>
		</subimages>
		<date>13/04/2015</date>
		<author>Yash Purohit</author>
	</article>	
	<article>
		<topic>Python Is The Language To Learn </topic>
        <category>software</category>
		<hits>9</hits>
		<likes>1</likes>
		<half>Many of the amateur programmers are in a dilemma of whether to learn which language. Read to learn more.</half>
		<quarter>Why learn python? Because it&#x2019;s awesome. Well that&#x2019;s the main reason to learn python. But you would like to know some more features of python. Besides being awesome, python will teach you how to think like a professional programmer.</quarter>
		<paramain>Many of the beginner programmers are in a dilemma of whether to learn which language. This confusion arises when one has already learned the basics of low or medium level programming language. Here, we would clear your confusion by showing you the merits of the foremost programming language at the moment and also of the future. That&#x2019;s the reason why python is considered as the language of the future.</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[Now the answer to the main question, why learn python? Because it&#x2019;s awesome. Well that&#x2019;s the main reason to learn python. But you would like to know some more features of python. Besides being awesome, python will teach you how to think like a professional programmer.<br /><br/> Also, python is the most reader friendly language at the moment. There is no reason to remember arcane syntax of different things, rather you can completely focus on the development. With being awesome and reader friendly, python is also an extremely powerful language. ]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[There&#x2019;s a reason why NASA and ISRO, two of the leading organisations in space research programmes, use python as their core programming language. So, now it would be clear that learning the basics of python programming language wouldn&#x2019;t be a heroic task.<br /><br/> But what after that? Once you have got the basics, one might get bored with outputting text, and numbers. This happens in any programming language. But here&#x2019;s where powerful libraries of python come into play. We all know what a library is, it is a collection of various books.<br /><br/> Similarly, python provides you with predefined functions to do specific tasks. Using them in you program, you can achieve anything and everything. Like, if you want to do stuff regarding images and graphics, Python Imaging Library will come to your rescue. If you want to tweak with the networks, then URL library will help you out. That&#x2019;s how anything can be achieved. ]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3>From years of hard work of the programming community, python has become one of the most powerful programming languages. Most of the programs of YouTube have been implemented using python. And same is with the case with google database. So, there you go. Start learning python in peace!</fullpara3>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article8.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>null</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article8a.png</image2>
			<image3>null</image3>
		</subimages>
		<date>12/04/2015</date>
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>
	</article>	
		<article>
		<topic>HTC One E8: Wallet Friendly Version Of M8</topic>
		<category>miscellaneous</category>
		<hits>28</hits>
		<likes>4</likes>
		<half>Probably the most exclusive and strikingly enhanced transformation of a flagship by HTC. It is being noted as the sibling of metallic M8.</half>
		<quarter>HTC One E8 has a polycarbonate body which makes it a slightly lighter version of M8. Also, it is quoted as &#x2018;plastic M8&#x2019;, but the sideline is this that E8 is in no way behind the M8 as far as performance is concerned . </quarter>
		<paramain>Probably the most exclusive and strikingly enhanced transformation of a flagship by HTC. It is being truly noted as the sibling of metallic M8. Apart from the ultrapixel camera which has been replaced in the E8 by a 13MP camera and the polycarbonate body, it is pretty much the same.</paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Design:</p> <br/>HTC has always been a design specialist since it mesmerized the world with spectacular front facing dual speakers in it’s One series. Nevertheless it’s sleek and magnetizing body type is also very popular right now.<br/><br/>HTC One E8 has a polycarbonate body which makes it a slightly lighter version of M8. Although, it is quoted as ‘plastic M8’, but the sideline is this, that E8 is in no way behind the M8 as far as performance is concerned.<br/><br/>Repetitive tests show that E8 has been performing identically as the BIG M8, hence HTC here provides with a low price high end phone.<br/><br/>Although, a downside of its body is that it is scratch-prone , but seldom we use a phone without a back cover.]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Camera and Sound:</p><br/>13MP is quiet common figure in today’s mobile phone segment. The other more reliable criteria for the comparison of the camera stength is PPI( pixels per inch). Here, E8 provides a whopping 441ppi which is rather a high camera efficiency compared to the variants with the same megapixel notation. The camera comes with an excellent HDR mode resulting in a wonderful photography experience in certain situations.<br/><br/>Its exclusive Boomsound speakers are an enthralling feature of its design structure. Moreover these front facing speakers add to listening experience to the user. It has become a select design trait for HTC smartphones now.]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Software and Hardware:</p><br/>E8 runs on the 2.5 Ghz quad-core Qualcomm Snapdragon 801 SoC, exactly the as the M8. It is supported by 2GB RAM, 16GB internal storage, expandable upto 128GB through SD card.<br/><br/>It comes with Android 4.4.2 with the latest SENSE 6 UI. Apart from this, HTC Blinkfeed is a salient feature which basically acts as newsreader. Blinkfeed can be customized to stay tuned with facebook, twitter and other social updates.<br/><br/>Software updates has been an issue for HTC. Though, promised to release the Lollipop update within 90 days of the Google release, for E8 it is still hanging on the line.]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">User Experience and Battery Life:</p><br/>HTC has perhaps the best UI , enriched with a range of exclusive  inbuilt apps such as FitBit which works with a wearable fitness device to track and analyse your fitness. <br/><br/>Zoe is yet another camera application which has an inbuilt feature to gather images and convert them into a video. The theme and background score of the video are customizable. But this feature is limited upto 16 images only. <br/><br/>Scribble is a note taking app with a striking variety of templates.<br/><br/>As far as longetivity of usage is concerned, the 2600MAh battery works very easily throughout the day with heavy 3G usage. Although E8 has a slightly concerning heating issue at times of regular usage or during charging.<br/><br/>Additionally, the gesture controls are exceptionally handy to use. Double Tap to wake and Swipe features can be an enriching experience for the user. ]]></fullpara4>
			<fullpara5><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Conclusion:</p><br/>Apart from the fact that it is the replica of a flagship, it is undoubtedly better than other phones of this price range. It is premium phone which is a bit wallet friendly for the features it provides.<br/><br/>So, if you wanna have a premium experience without shelling out huge bucks, you can go for it.]]></fullpara5>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article9.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article9a.png</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article9b.png</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article9c.png</image3>
			<image4>Pictures/article9d.png</image4>
			<image5>null</image5>
		</subimages>
		<date>12/04/2015</date>
		<author>Rishabh Yadav</author>
	</article>
	<article>
		<topic>OnePlus One Review</topic>
		<category>miscellaneous</category>
		<hits>15</hits>
		<likes>2</likes>
		<half><![CDATA[A self-styled “flagship killer”. A Developer’s partner. A Low cost beast.]]></half>
		<quarter>Most of you might have heard about the Oneplus One. It&#x2019;s a smartphone, featuring the best of everything at an unbelievably low price, which emerged out of nowhere and has managed to beat many of the tall order smartphone companies.</quarter>
		<paramain><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">What is so special about it?</p><br/><br/>A high quality phone, for a price tag of 22k, runs Cyanogenmod – a modded version of Android which is popular with tinkerers, out of the box. It’s a nexus in everything but the name. It sports a 5.5 inch ~400 PPI screen, driven by 2.5GHz Snapdragon 801 processor and powered by hunky 3100 mAh battery! For such a price tag and such features, it’s a damn good deal.]]></paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Design:</p><br/>The moment one would lay his fingers or eyes on the phone, he could tell it’s a high-quality design, almost impossible for such a price tag. The screen is raised slightly over the silver edged body, providing your fingers limitless screen and fun. And it looks good as well. On the back, the beast boasts of a fabric sort of texture. <br/><br/>At the time when 30k smartphones feature a glossy-cheap plastic-y back, oneplus one has a strange yet unique back cover. For some, this adds a royal feel to their phone but, some set it down due to fear of getting stained. All in all, this move has been welcomed by the group of smartphone enthusiasts. <br/><br/>Besides its silver edges, back and the screen, oneplus one has impressed everyone with the accessories it is sold with. The micro USB cable cloth-coated cables a run for their money and is untanglable! It is one of the most badass micro USB cable I have seen.]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Display:</p><br/>The screen is a 1080 x 1920 pixel IPS LCD display, comes with a protection of Corning Gorilla Glass 3, looks great in all scenarios. It still lacks somewhere in the contrast when compared to AMOLED displays, but all in all, its pretty. The brightness is never a problem. The highest brightness setting of the smartphone can tackle sunny days pretty well. <br/><br/>At the bottom of the screen, there are three touchscreen hardware button, one each for Home, Settings and Back. This is a feature long lost on android devices, and some users might find it unattractive or not useful. Thanks to Cyanogenmod, you can turn them off and switch to software buttons as per your wish.]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Camera:</p><br/>Oneplus one boasts of a 13 megapixel rear camera, capable of capturing low light images and recording 4k videos. There’s a dual flash just below the rear camera. The preinstalled camera app on the phone gives the traditional Google camera a run for its money. The front camera is a 5 megapixel camera and is capable of recording full HD videos and capturing amazing selfies. The preinstalled camera, comes with real-time filters. ]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Battery:</p><br/>The Battery in the oneplus one is a non-removable Li-ion battery with a hunky capacity of 3100 mAh. This is enough to power your smartphone throughout the day inspite of hefty usage. It can provide a screen-on-time of around 7-8 hours once fully charged. The charger of the oneplus one can charge the phone amazingly fast. But there’s a catch. <br/><br/>If you use just a random charger, even if it is of Nexus 5, your phone will charge very slowly. But its not the case with the provides charger and a damn good looking charger too.]]></fullpara4>
			<fullpara5><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Operating System:</p><br/>The beast runs on a software designed specifically for the hardware of the phone. The combination of Cyanogenmod and Oneplus has put together awesome hardware and software. It comes out of the box running on modded Android 4.4.x, named as Cyanogenmod 11s, dubbed as cm11s. This cm11s allows its users to customize anything and everything. <br/><br/>Users can change their boot animations, their themes, their icons, their navigation bar etc, without the need of rooting or installing separate launchers.]]></fullpara5>	
			<fullpara6><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Final Call:</p><br/>With all the above mentioned Hardware and Software capabilities, and that too at such a price tag, the oneplus can give any phone a run for its money. The tagline ‘Flagship killer’ is justified by the specs provides and the price range. <br/><br/>For all those looking for a smartphone that would give premium feel, sport all the advanced features, run any game, provide a long battery life and last for a longer time, oneplus one is the solution. Plus, you won’t have to shell out a fortune to buy the device.]]></fullpara6>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article10.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article10a.png</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article10b.png</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article10c.png</image3>
			<image4>Pictures/article10d.png</image4>
			<image5>Pictures/article10e.png</image5>
			<image6>null</image6>
		</subimages>
		<date>12/04/2015</date>
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>
	</article>	
	<article>
		<topic>Lenovo A6000 Review</topic>
		<category>miscellaneous</category>
		<hits>10</hits>
		<likes>1</likes>
		<half>Its first of a kind phone which offers 4G,quad core processor and some other great features.</half>
		<quarter>So Lenovo new in the mobile are here with their new phone &#x201C;Lenovo A6000&#x201D;.Its first of a kind phone which offers 4G,quad core processor and some other great features in the price tag of just 7000/-</quarter>
		<paramain><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">So what’s so special about it?</p><br/>Lenovo launched its low budget phone in Feb 2015 on flipkart for 7000/- reviews were awesome, in fact they claim of selling more than 10000 pieces in just in some seconds! Okay that is way to cool!]]></paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Design:</p><br/>It’s a candyshape slim phone; an added advantage is the phone's low weight of 128g, which makes it comfortable for single-handed usage. Great work on the weight Lenovo! The black rear cover has a smooth matte finish which feels good to touch. ]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Display:</p><br/>The 5-inch IPS LCD screen has a resolution of 720x1280, which is the maximum one can find on budget smartphones. At first glance, the screen does look vibrant but that is mainly due to the colorful Vibe UI Android skin. Lenovo hasn't used protective glass on the display of the A6000 which is a bit of a letdown. <br/><br/>The three capacitive touch navigation buttons are placed right below the display and were pretty responsive. Unfortunately, the keys are not backlit.]]></fullpara2>
			<fullpara3><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Camera:</p><br/>Lenovo A600 has a rear camera of 8mp with flash and front camera of 2mp from which you can click decent selfies. The phone features Lenovo's own camera app that offers settings for all optical attributes, HDR (including auto-HDR), Panorama and Timer modes, among others. <br/><br/>Images captured by the camera in day light turned out well with decent level of detail, accurate colour reproduction and good contrast. Images shot in low-light were grainy but comparatively better than other phones available in the same segment.]]></fullpara3>
			<fullpara4><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Battery:</p><br/>Battery in the Lenovo A600 is a removable Li-Po 2300 mAh battery, it's enough for survival of the phone for a day before you can charge it for next day. The charger us simple one, no fancy one. It takes 3hrs to charge your phone  for 0-100%. ]]></fullpara4>
			<fullpara5><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Specifications and Software:</p><br/>Lenovo has packed the latest 64-bit Snapdragon 410 SoC inside the A6000. It is a 1.2GHz quad-core processor with integrated Adreno 306 GPU. The phone has 1GB of RAM and 8GB of internal storage space. In case the 8GB space doesn't suffice, one can add up to 32GB more using a microSD card. <br/><br/>Lenovo uses its Vibe UI skin on top of Android 4.4.4 (Kitkat).Users can also use other skins like Google Launcher or any other launchers.<br/><br/>Phone is also packed with Dolby twin speakers which have loud sound output that offers clarity even at higher levels. You can choose among four preset settings modes or customize the equalizer settings via the Dolby app. <br/><br/>However, the speaker outlet is located at the back and unfortunately; the sound gets muffled when the phone lies at its back.]]></fullpara5>
			<fullpara6><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Final Verdict:</p><br/>At Rs 6,999, the Lenovo A6000 offers excellent features to price ratio. This is not to say the A6000 is without flaws; the display could have had protective glass and the cameras could have been better. But it’s a great low budget 4G phone with some decent features. You can load heavy games and have the fun, it won’t disappoint.]]></fullpara6>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article11.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article11a.png</image1>
			<image2>Pictures/article11b.png</image2>
			<image3>Pictures/article11c.png</image3>
			<image4>Pictures/article11d.png</image4>
			<image5>Pictures/article11e.png</image5>
			<image6>null</image6>
		</subimages>
		<date>10/04/2015</date>
		<author>Yash Purohit</author>
	</article>
	<article>
		<topic>Raspberry Pi</topic>
		<category>hardware</category>
		<hits>15</hits>
		<likes>3</likes>
		<half>Spectacular Credit-card sized single-boarded computers!</half>
		<quarter>The Raspberry Pi is a series of credit card sized computers developed by Raspberry Pi Foundation. They are designed on a single board so that they don&#x2019;t occupy a lot of space and are available for a cheap rate.</quarter>
		<paramain><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">What is so special?</p><br/>The most special thing about the Raspberry Pi computers, is that they are single boarded computer, loaded with basic features and sufficient processing capacity and are available for as low as $20! These mini-computers provide processors, RAM and graphics too. And they also provide sockets for MicroSD for boot media and Storage expansion! <br/><br/>In this generation of ever evolving computers, Raspberry Pi has come to the rescue of those people who can’t afford laptops and Desktops but need them for their work. Raspberry Pi has also allowed many schools to teach basic computer science to their students without shelling out a fortune, as these magical boards are available from $20 to $50. Yes, they are this cheap!]]></paramain>
		<paras>
			<fullpara1><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Models and Specs:</p><br/><br/>There are basically two models- Pi 1 and Pi 2. Although, the Pi 1 is available in three variants.<br/><br/><p class="subheadingofarticle">Raspberry Pi 1 :</p><br/><br/>Operating System : Linux, RISC OS, FreeBSD, NetBSD, Plan 9 and Inferno. Unfortunately, the first model of Raspberry pi didn’t support windows operating system, but they have added it in their latest model!<br/><br/>CPU : 700 MHz single core<br/><br/>Memory : 256 MB(Model A, A+) and 512 MB(Model B)<br/><br/>Storage : 4 GB IC Chip and MicroSDHC slot.<br/><br/>Graphic : Broadcom VideoCore<br/><br/>Power : 1.5 to 3 W]]></fullpara1>
			<fullpara2><![CDATA[<p class="subheadingofarticle">Raspberry Pi 2:</p><br/>Operating System : Same as Raspberry Pi 1 + Windows 10, Ubuntu and Android.<br/><br/>CPU : 900 MHz quad core<br/><br/>Memory : 1 GB<br/><br/>Storage : MicroSHDC Slot<br/><br/>Graphics : Broadcom VideoCore<br/><br/>Power : 4.0 W]]></fullpara2>
		</paras>	
		<imagemain>Pictures/article12.png</imagemain>
		<subimages>
			<image1>Pictures/article12a.png</image1>
			<image1>Pictures/article12b.png</image1>
		</subimages>
		<date>10/04/2015</date>
		<author>Sarjak Thakkar</author>
	</article>
	
	
</allhalf>
